Guide to the Department of Anthropology, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Anthropology, Yale University, records
1935-2014
RU 333
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
18.5
The records consist of faculty and personnel files, minutes, budgets, chronological files, and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Anthropology.
Yale University. Department of Anthropology
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Department of Anthropology, 1997 and 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by type of material.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of faculty and personnel files, minutes, budgets, chronological files, and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Anthropology.
Anthropology -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Anthropology
- Records, circa 1935-1988; Accession 1998-A-011
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023
  - Departmental files, circa 1935-1945 (Box 1)
  - Departmental files, circa 1935-1945 (Box 2)
  - Faculty minutes, 1957-1982 (Box 3)
  - Budget, 1979-1987 (Box 3)
  - Budget, 1979-1987 (Box 4)
  - Annual reports, 1953-1978 (Box 4)
  - Teaching fellows, 1979-1983 (Box 5)
  - Student teaching, 1972-1982 (Box 5)
  - Chron files, 1984-1989 (Box 5)
  - Staff files, 1984-1989 (Box 5)
  - Past faculty, circa 1953-1978 (Box 6)
    - A-D, 1950-1988 (Box 7)
    - E-Mi, 1950-1988 (Box 8)
    - P-Po, 1950-1988 (Box 9)
    - Pr-Z, 1950-1988 (Box 10)
- Faculty and Personnel files, 1948-2014; Accession 2016-A-025